They say this quantum state thing
他们说这个量子态的玩意
will soon cover this place.
很快会覆盖这里
What should we do?
我们该怎么办
The only thing we can do is
唯一能做的可能就是
to keep it away from us.
让它远离我们
Hurry
快
go to the control panel
上操作台去
and start up the nuclear power station at the top of the ladder.
启动了天梯顶部的核电站
The quantum body will be attracted to it.
量子体就会被吸引
We succeeded.
我们成功了
Alert.
警报
Hydraulic brake system malfunction.
液压制动系统发生故障
The main structure of the high-altitude transfer station is about to be damaged.
高空中转站主结构即将损毁
Alert. Oxygen remaining 65%.
警报氧气剩余量65%
Alert.
警报
Air leak and depressurization detected in extravehicular spacesuit.
检测到舱外航天服漏气失压
Please take immediate safety measures.
请立即采取安全保障措施
Alert.
警报
Oxygen remaining 55%.
氧气剩余量55%
Oxygen remaining 48%.
氧气剩余量48%
This should be it.
应该是这个了
Ding Yi
丁仪
What will happen when they combine?
它们合起来后会怎样
Either it will successfully leave
要么成功离开
or
要么
it will accelerate the diffusion.
扩散加速
Chairman
主席
What about the ladder base and the low-altitude station?
那天梯基座和低空站怎么办
In case...
万一
He once asked me.
他曾经问过我
Alert.
警报
Energy remaining 9%.
能源余量9%
Do you have confidence in me?
是不是对他没有信心
I didn't answer directly.
我没有直接回答
Alert.
警报
Energy remaining 8%.
能源余量8%
To be honest
坦白说
I've had doubts too.
我也动摇过
But now I have confidence.
但现在我有信心
Alert.
警报
Energy remaining 7%.
能源余量7%
because he is facing something
因为他面对的
that we cannot imagine.
是我们无法想象的事情
Alert.
警报
Energy remaining 6%.
能源余量6%
And he has come this far.
还走到了现在这一步
If a Wallfacer can die and come back to life
一个面壁者如果能置之死地而后生
Alert.
警报
Energy remaining 5%.
能源余量5%
The Wallfacer plan can still be carried out.
那面壁计划也能
Alert.
警报
Energy remaining 3%.
能源余量3%
The shielding layer of the quantum body starts to shift
量子体的屏蔽层开始偏移
Hurry up.
快上去
Bring that kid back.
接那小子回来
Gravity is back.
引力又来了
That was fast.
这么快
I got it under control.
我搞定了
Are you okay?
你没事吧
Zhuang Yan.
庄颜
Push against the door and hold onto the handrails tightly.
压挤门舱防谨杆栏护防紧抓
Search for a fixed position and look for nearby personnel.
位定固找寻近就员人有所
The paralyzed system exerts a heavy force on the ring.
痪瘫统系力重环一空高报警
Alert. The E-ring and the F-ring has been closed off to personnel.
警报已封闭在E环道F环道内的人员
Don't block the way.
别挡路
Start self-help and mutual aid now.
立即开展自救互助
Go to the other side and wait for rescue.
来回边那往别
Stay calm and stay safe.
援救待等心耐
Keep calm and keep people here.
静冷持保请员人困被
Run quickly and don't stop.
跑快着愣别
Prepare for oxygen deficiency and temperature loss.
氧缺温失防谨
Access to emergency supplies and reserves.
资物急应备储取获近就
What's the matter?
了么怎边那
Don't stop, let personnel in the F-ring and E-ring pass.
留停勿请员人有所道环F道环E
Ah, there are injured rescue personnel.
啊人救员伤有
The danger is high, safety is paramount.
险风全安大重在存
Pressure loss, temperature loss in the F-ring
压失温失道环F
Alert. Damaged structure Main Port II Ring 2 on High Alert.
毁损构结主港力重号II环一空高 报警
I'm leaving now.
我下丢别
The seal.
了舱封要
Luo Ji.
罗辑
Can you hear me?
能听到我吗
Visual enhancements enabled.
视觉增强已启用
Luo Ji.
罗辑
Luo Ji, can you hear me?
罗辑你能听到我吗
I just had a dream.
刚刚我好像做了一个梦
Everything in the dream
梦里的一切
was so real.
都那么真实
But I couldn't find you.
但我找不到你
Don’t worry.
别担心
I'm here.
我在这儿
No matter what time or space.
无论哪个时空
No matter how many possibilities.
无论有多少可能
You will always come back to me.
你都会回来我身边
Just like now.
像现在这样
You took such a great risk for me.
因为你为我冒这么大的风险
Maybe my happiness
或许我的幸福
really is part of your plan.
真的是你计划的一部分
Isn't it?
对吗
I want to give you all my happiness and joy.
我要把所有幸福和快乐都给你
If time could stop
如果时间能停止
Just one more second
再多一秒
One second is enough.
一秒钟就够了
The electromagnetic wave readings have appeared.
电磁波读数出现
The shielding layer is migrating upwards.
屏蔽层正向上迁移
The signal from the high-altitude station can be searched.
高空站信号能搜索到了
Where is the quantum body?
量子体的位置呢
It's following the auxiliary nuclear power station
跟着副核电站
towards deep space.
往深空方向去了
Is the Wallfacer safe?
面壁者安全吗
We are currently searching for spacesuit signals.
正在搜索宇航服信号
No need
不用
I see them now.
我看到他们了
This guy is really lucky
这小子命真大
He actually passed through between two quantum bodies.
居然从两个量子体中间穿过去了
Only in your eyes
只有在你目光里
do I feel that there is another side to the universe.
我才感到宇宙有另外一面
I feel that space-time
我感到时空
is collapsing towards us.
向我们坍缩
The stars are vibrating in the galaxy
星海在振动
and all of this
所有这一切
is engulfed in the light of love's creation.
都湮没在爱的创世之光里
The night sky is a black sphere
夜空是个黑色的球面
studded with countless silver stars.
镶着无数银色的星星
Inside there
那里面
is the world we live in
是我们生活的世界
with many mountains like the Greater Khingan
很多大兴安岭这样的山脉
Stretching far and wide
向四周
in all directions.
延伸到很远
Perhaps this is humanity's sunset.
这或许是人类的落日
But I remember in Qijiadian
但我记得在齐家屯
When it got dark
天黑的时候
sometimes people would light a lamp
有时还有人点着灯
then there was nothing to fear.
就不用怕了
The darkness is also gentle.
黑暗也是柔和的
The light from the charcoal fire
那炭火的光
looks so beautiful.
多好看啊